323.423.4937 Los Angeles, California tduppstadt@gmail.com

http://tduppstadt.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/thom-duppstadt

I have 15+ years professional experience in design and development of online and desktop applications. Focusing on rapid development producing clean, readable, and efficient code with attention to best practices. Building modular architectures to ensure maintainable, reusable, scalable applications. My background in design combined with my extensive development experience give me a unique skill set that would be an asset to any development team.

Work History

Lunchbox 2012 to 2015

Lunchbox is a shopper engagement agency that turns shoppers into buyers by creating and connecting custom content to drive sales through retail partners.

Roles: Senior Front End Developer on Innovations team

Accomplishments:

- Sole front-end developer for Firestarter, a responsive, cross-browser, click tracking, blogger engagement tool to promote client campaigns including Kraft and Thomas & Friends. Developed on a custom MVC architecture using RESTful interfaces and Scrum methodologies.
 - Built a custom Admin site to populate campaign assets and manage click tracking, fraud, and finances for participating bloggers.
 - Researched technologies and implemented features include data graphing using D3 and Olark live chat for customer support.
 - Read consumer and client feedback, presented solutions to address issues and improvements
 - o Researched related concepts to compare the competition, features, and costs.
 - Ran experiments and pitched ideas on how to recreate and mitigate against threats such as click fraud.
 - Adapted integration of the RESTful interface migrating the back end from Ruby to NodeJS.
- Developed Elite Receipt. A receipt scanning rewards system used to promote dozens of custom branded high profile campaigns including Hot Wheels, Axe, Kraft, Crystal Light, Suave, and Tresemme.
 - o Refactored mobile app for fast, efficient and unobtrusive code redesign.
 - Designed and built desktop app for full CMS customization using my own custom framework.
 - Built custom CMS migrated from JSON and integrated with mobile and desktop applications.
- Initiated and implemented improvements to company-wide tracking system for the analytics team by adopting an event system.
- Mentored junior developers in standardization of code using prototypes, closures and build scripts, and grasping technologies such as RequireJS, GruntJS, doT and SASS
- Developed websites, CMS, and web applications using a personal custom MVC boilerplate including JQuery, RequireJS, GruntJS, doT, Greensock, SASS
- Developed a fully dynamic scalable, customizable, brand marketing module. Featuring 1 to 3
 modules displayed in an accordion style menu. Sub modules include product browser, video
 browser, and Q & A module.

Tools: Javascript, JQuery, RequireJS, GruntJS, Bootstrap, doT, Handlebars, Greensock, Hammer, Backbone, D3, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, IIS, Glue, MVC, Photoshop, Git, Jira, Confluence, MongoDB, Docker

Blitz Agency 2015 to 2016

Mixing art and science to turn brands into favorites.

Roles: Senior Front End Developer

Accomplishments:

- Key player of a small team responsible for the complete reboot of the American Association of Critical-Care Nurses (AACN) website https://www.aacn.org/. Creating pages, templates and modular components throughout the site.
- Took initiative to refine development environment from 2 repos to a single repo to improve speed, efficiency and reduce errors during development.
- I've been involved with technical planning and UI support, also providing estimates.
- Responsible for maintenance, improvements, and revisions for FX Networks' official site (http://www.fxnetworks.com/) and Simpsons' official site (http://www.simpsonsworld.com/).
 - FX site optimization minifying and concatenating HTML/JS/CSS
 - o Upgraded and abstracted site wide SEO optimization using JSON-LD.
 - o Migrated both sites to native Win10 apps.
- Created FX Networks' promotional email newsletters compatible against multiple desktop and mobile email clients.

Tools: Javascript, JQuery, RequireJS, GruntJS, Bazaarvoice, Backbone, Marrionette, Handlebars, Grunt, Gulp, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, AWS, PHP, Git, Sitecore, Slack, Jira, Trello

NuMedia Innovations Inc.

2004 to 2012

NuMedia Innovations is an award winning marketing group geared primary towards to the medical industry. NuMedia Provides digital solutions for business, training tools, trade shows, internet development, and augmented reality

Roles: Web Developer, Senior Flash Developer, Multimedia Designer, Graphic Designer, Animator, Video Editor/Compositor

Accomplishments:

Software Development

- Implemented a custom MVC design pattern for Exploria using Javascript to develop a series of fully animated iPad web applications geared toward insurance agents in the field.
- Personally developed web remote driven video presentations and quizzes for CME credit, training tools, games, and marketing applications.
- Built proprietary MVC framework for Flash used to develop all company Flash desktop/wep applications.
- Created Flash game engine for custom arcade console used in Florida Hospital.
- Developed Flash based kiosk applications for massive touchless kiosk technologies
 - o Oversaw the implementation for convention presentation.
- Researched and Developed AR technologies for further marketing company technologies.
- In charge of UI/UX development in terms of both design and technical implementation, developing over 50 cutting-edge desktop and web applications.

Graphic Design, 2D/3D Motion Graphics, Video Production

- In charge of UI design mocks for ALL company websites and applications. Created 100s of design mocks throughout my career.
- Personally produced and created video presentations with responsibilities of storyboarding, animatics, live video editing, compositing, 2D/3D asset development, animation of all assets including visual SFX, particle effects, and post production.

Tools: Javascript, JQuery, Greensock, HTML5, CSS3, IIS, ASP, Flash AS3, Papervision, ARToolkit, MDM Zinc, Director, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Vegas Video, 3D Studio Max, TortoiseSVN, OnTime

The Ballistic Pixel Lab

2000-2004

Ballistic Pixel Lab is a post-production graphic arts company. The company offers 3D modeling/animation, 2D graphics, visual effects, cinematic development, video editing and web development.

Roles: Multimedia Developer, Graphic Designer, Animator, Video Editor/Compositor

Accomplishments:

Software Development

- Designed and programmed 20+ cross-platform desktop applications.
- Single-handedly designed and developed a 3D visualization software application for Mohawk Design Centers.
- Spearheaded and developed 3D visualization techniques including integration of a 3D game engine, launching a breakthrough in development efficiency.

3D Game Cinematics

 Took a lead role in the production of the 3D game cinematic for the PC and console release of Sarge's War. Produced animatic from storyboards. In charge of character and environment layout for 2/3 of entire production. Took lead in 2/3 of the production's camera animation. In charge of editing and post production of 3/4 of the entire cinematic, maintaining pace, impact, and integrity for the final production.

2D/3D Motion Graphics

- Modeled and integrated 3D and 2D elements to produce more than 50 high impact NTSC and HD
 resolution broadcast quality seamless looping backgrounds for Digital Juice.
- Animated background appearances include: (3) 45th Grammy Awards, (4) American Idol, NBC television network, WOWK-TV Weather Doppler News, and the NCHL Orlando Seals in-game team introduction and promotional advertisement

Technologies: Director, Flash AS2, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Vegas Video, 3D Studio Max

Education

•	Associate of Science in Digital Media - Salutatorian		
	Full Sail Real World Education	Digital Media	2000-2001
•	Ohio State University	Graphic Arts	1995-1996